# Ronan Sprake

19 Collingwood Close, Norwich, NR9 3QE 07944 277678 / ronansprake@gmail.com

# **Profile**

I'm an accomplished UX Designer with extensive in-house, agency and start-up experience. I design inclusive customer experiences with Agile and User Centred Design practices that deliver creative, sustainable solutions while remaining business focused and value driven.

My portfolio: https://ronansprake.co.uk/portfolio-rsprake.pdf

# **Key Skills & Attributes**

- Interaction design with a focus on usability, accessibility and information architecture (IA)
- Tools including Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD / CC, Axure, Invision, Proto, Zeplin, Jira and Trello
- Conducting user testing and research methodologies (qualitative and quantitative)
- A collaborative, pragmatic approach to design, strategic change and evolving requirements
- Encouraging transparency, trust and candid feedback to challenge my thinking
- Supportive and confident mentor for junior and mid-level designers
- Experience with a wide variety of web development, native apps and custom software
- Understanding of legal and compliance processes within strongly regulated environments

# **Employment History**

#### **Lead UX Designer - Upside Money**

March 2021 - Present

I joined an early stage startup to experience a Techstars Accelerator Programme, leading the research and design of innovative products based on Open Banking technology, shaping the direction of our services.

- Executed research and the iterative design of fully compliant customer experiences across iOS,
  Web and B2B SaaS platforms, representing the voice of the customer at all stages
- Used Lean UX practices to facilitate fast-paced collaboration within a remote team
- Established Design System foundations to introduce consistency and accessibility standards
- Uncovered and iteratively solved iOS onboarding issues, reducing failure demand
- Built strong relationships with the engineering team, ensuring user stories are clearly understood and that design and development work hand-in-hand to achieve the best outcomes
- Created a proposition testing framework, including surveys and interviews with B2B partners to understand pain points, analyse results and collate insights

### Senior UX Designer - Aviva

March 2017 - March 2021

Designing delightful customer journeys and services across Aviva's digital estate, enhancing experiences for over 31 million customers worldwide.

 Principal UX on Aviva's Global Design System, used by 120 designers in 9 countries. I contributed designs while managing backlog for 2 UX designers, providing priorities and direction

- Produced service blueprints, journey maps, IA, sketches, wireframes and high fidelity prototypes for a variety of products, including quote & payment, claims, investments and data-rich systems
- Estimated time and resource requirements for projects of all sizes
- Increased cross-discipline collaboration, leading to a ~50% increase in my team's sprint velocity
- Delivered actionable heuristic reviews for strategic partnerships (Barclays, HSBC and Santander)
- Interviewed and mentored designers, I also gave talks to groups of college and university students
- Presented Accessibility Champions Group sessions, promoting WCAG standards across Digital
- Gave skill-share presentations at monthly design meet-ups in Hoxton (80 UX/UI designers)

#### **UX Manager - Soak (digital agency)**

Jul 2015 - Mar 2017

Realising my strength and passion was for UX design, I worked with global brands including Red Bull, GE, The Economist and Games Workshop.

- Recruited, managed and mentored 2 UX designers and 2 UI developers
- Organised and led design workshops, lab and guerrilla testing
- Delivered successful design pitches (London, Paris, Salzburg)

## Lead UI Developer - Soak

Jan 2012 - Jul 2015

Led creative product builds using Angular and React for clients including HSBC, IBM and Adnams.

**UI Developer - Soak** 

Jan 2009 – Jan 2012

The first employee of a highly successful agency, I built design systems and emails for GE and Nissan.

#### **Full Stack Developer - Digital Overload**

Nov 2007 - Jan 2009

A digital agency, I built digital products while training in Git, HTML, CSS, JS, PHP and MySQL.

## IT Technician - Permastore

Oct 2005 - Nov 2007

Managed critical infrastructure, I also designed custom touchscreen and barcode interfaces.

# **Education**

Aviva	Aviva Certificate in General Insurance	2018
Open University	Certificate in Web Applications Development (Distinction)	2006 - 2008
University of Lancaster	History BA (Hons), (2:1)	2002 - 2005

# **Interests**

In the rare moments my young family isn't keeping me busy, I enjoy films (I've never seen Star Wars, please don't hold that against me) and I started baking during lockdown, with varying degrees of success.